# 哈喽大家好我是王刚
Hi everyone, I'm Wang Gang
# 这些年有很多粉丝问我如何才能够成为一个合格的厨师
Over the years, many fans have been asking me how to become a qualified chef
# 现在我就用我的早期经历跟大家分享一下
Now I want to share my experience from when I first get started
# 刚开始的时候作为一个什么都不懂的学徒一个门外汉来说
At the very beginning, as a new apprentice, or a newbie, who knows nothing at all
# 看到打荷，配菜和灶上炒菜的师傅们各有各的技巧
You may notice that cooks of different stations have their own set of skills
# 一开始都特别的渴望早日能成为一个什么都懂而且技术好的师傅
And you'll be eager to become a skillful and knowledgeable master chef as soon as possible
# 所以就比较特别的着急和彷徨
So you'll feel anxious and confused
# 不知所措特别的迷茫
You may also get lost and don't know what to do
# 所以在这个视频我会跟大家快速分享一下如何正确的走上厨师长的道路
So I'm gonna share with you briefly about how to get on the right track to becoming a head chef
# 我记得我刚开始出来的时候比较小
I remember that I was relatively young when I started my career
# 差不多也就是14-15岁的样子吧
At that time, I was about 14-15 years old
# 就算给我一个炒锅让我马上上去炒菜我又能炒什么呢
Even if I was given a wok and told to cook at once, what could I cook anyway?
# 这个时候我连最基本的东西都不知道
I didn't even know the most basic thing
# 所以说越着急越没有用急功近利会事得其反
So it is completely useless to be anxious. Rushing yourself to achieve quick success only slows you down
# 首先让自己变得有功底那就是沉下心来把杂工的本职工作干好
The very first thing to do is to lay a solid foundation, that is, be patient and do your job well as a kitchen porter/dishwasher
# 能够吃苦耐劳脏活累活抢着干
You need to get your hands dirty and be the first first person to take on any difficult task
# 只有这样师傅才能够喜欢你愿意去带你
Only in this way will the master chefs like you and teach you
# 这样才能够有更多的机会学习打荷，切菜，摆盘
In this way, you'll have more chances to learn chopping, prepping and plating
# 只有把刀功练好把炒锅练好
You need to practice and master your knife skills and wok-tossing skill
# 好要会一些像样的摆盘
Also, you should have some knowledge of decent food presentation
# 在合适的时间和地点再找上灶的机会
Then, when the time is right, seek a chance to cook on the hot line
# 要懂的不怕脏不怕累多付出汗水
Don't be afraid of getting dirty and tired. Make painstaking efforts
# 一旦有炒菜的机会来了要把握好
Once you have the opportunity to demonstrate your stovetop cooking skills, seize it
# 必须拿这个基本功练扎实
You must have a solid foundation
# 比如说翻锅和调味
Such as wok-tossing and seasoning
# 还有掌握油温这些基本的常识
As well as controlling oil temperature
# 最后呢我建议大家就是做人不要太木讷
My final tip is: don't be shy, dull or inarticulate
# 要会看事儿
You need to be observant and read the room
# 比如说师傅渴了就给他端点水送点茶之类的
For example, if your master is thirsty, fetch him/her a drink
# 比如说师傅炒完菜当然是很累了马上下来了之后呢
Or, when he/she just finishes cooking and shows exhaustion
# 就接过他手中的卫生去搞干净
You should take over and clean up for them
# 但是前提是自己的本质工作提前完成的情况下
Of course, you must have done your own job
# 要不然自己的事情都没有做好又怎么去帮被人呢
If you can't complete your own tasks, how can you properly help others?
# 这样只会添乱
It will only make it worse
# 好了本期视频就到这里
Ok. That's the end of this video
# 下期视频我会为大家分享更多的厨师专业
I'll share with you more chef stories
# 或者是美食作家王刚的美食小技巧
...or cooking tips and trick in my next video
# 就到这里啦 拜拜
That's all. Bye-bye!